URGENT ALERT

Help Refugees and People in Health Crises

[DONATE](https://secure.projecthope.org/site/SPageNavigator/2024_07_MigrantHealth_web.html "DONATE") Close

* Our Solutions
    * We partner with communities, health care workers, and public health systems to ensure sustainable change.
        
* Global Reach
    * We equip health care workers with the skills and support they need to heal people and transform lives around the world.
        
* Get Involved
    * You can support our mission to help people access the health care they need to reach their full potential.

* Who we are

Search

Search for: 

Search for: 

* Our Solutions
* Global Reach
* Get Involved

* Who we are
    Back* [About Us](https://www.projecthope.org/about/)

Privacy Policy
==============

Project HOPE – the People-to-People Health Foundation (“Project HOPE” or “we”) respects the right to privacy of individuals (“you”) and is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust. This Privacy Policy explains the Project HOPE Privacy Principles, the type of personal data we collect, the legal basis and reason for collecting such information; how we share, transfer and secure personal data; and your privacy rights.

Personal data includes information relating to a living individual who can be directly or indirectly identified by the data such as name, address, contact details, gender, date of birth, geographic info, educational/school.

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Project HOPE commits to honoring the following privacy principles:

* We will collect and process personal data in a lawful, fair and transparent manner.
* We will collect and process personal data only for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes. The reason for collecting will be specified at the time of collection and personal data will only be used for the reason specified.
* We will collect and process personal data to the extent that it is adequate, relevant, and limited to what is necessary for the purpose of processing. We will only use data collected that is necessary for the task at hand. We will keep personal data in an identifiable form only as long as necessary to fulfill the stated purpose.
* We will ensure that all personal data is accurate and kept up-to-date and correct or deleted immediately when inaccurate.
* We will secure personal data by appropriate technical and organizational measures from unauthorized or unlawful processes, and against accidental loss, destruction, or damage.
* We will honor donor requests to remove their names and contact information from lists Project HOPE shares or sells.

**What Personal Data Do We Collect?**

Project HOPE has a global mission to promote the strengthening of health systems by addressing health problems, including infectious disease, non-communicable disease, maternal and child heath, and disaster/health crisis support by providing resources, training, and health awareness through global health programs. In order to carry out our mission, we collect the following personal and confidential data from individuals and organizations:

* Based on consent we collect personal information about clients benefiting from Project HOPE’s programs
* Based on contractual commitments we collect personal data from institutional partners
* Based on consent and contracts, we collect personal data from directors and volunteers
* Based on consent we collect personal data from our donors and supporters
* Based on OPT IN consent we collect personal information to access certain features on our website that allow you to send and receive information to and from us and to donate to us (we collect credit card information only for the purpose of processing your donation)
* Based on legitimate interests we collect personal data for personnel and financial operations

**Why Do We Collect Personal Data?**

We collect and otherwise use personal data for specific purposes that are limited to furthering our charitable mission. Project HOPE does not collect or otherwise use personal data without a legal requirement, contractual obligation, and/or express written consent.

The information we collect helps us to: (1) design and improve products and services that meet our clients’ needs; (2) monitor the effectiveness of our programs; (3) evaluate individual skill sets and match them to corresponding needs in the field; (4) track personal information of our clients so we can give them (or their health care providers) relevant and useful information; (6) conduct research in the aggregate in order to understand our global and regional impact; and (7) track personnel and financial operations for internal purposes.

When we collect personal data we will disclose the legal basis and purpose for collection, how it will be processed, and whether personal data will be shared with organizations that are related to us, with our service providers, and with our third-party partners. We may also share aggregated and anonymous data with our third-party partners and with the general public. Occasionally, we may be required by legal request, subpoena, government reporting obligation, or other legal process or obligation to disclose our clients’ private data. Similarly, as permitted by law, we may disclose the information we collect to fight fraud or to protect the rights or property of Project HOPE, our clients, our donors or others, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**Transfer of Personal Data**

In connection with any of the uses or sharing of personal data, we may transfer personal data internationally to an organization or location outside of the country in which the information is collected. Project HOPE will follow all data protection protocols required by applicable local laws and will adhere to the Project HOPE Privacy Principles.

**Security**

Project HOPE is committed to protecting your personal data against unlawful destruction, accidental loss or alteration, or unauthorized disclosure or access. First, we only collect and otherwise use personal data that is relevant to, proportional to and in furtherance of the stated purposes for which it is obtained. Second, we do not store your personal or sensitive information any longer than is necessary to satisfy those purposes. Third, when we store or otherwise use your personal or sensitive information, we use reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards that are designed to protect and secure private data adequately. For example:

* When you donate to Project HOPE via our website, your donation information is encrypted and transmitted by way of a secure connection (Note: No security systems are perfect, and we cannot guarantee the security of our clients’ information)
* We ensure that the entities with whom we share personal data have agreed to provide sufficient guarantees, in compliance with local law, to secure and protect that data
* We annually audit our Privacy Policy in order to ensure internal compliance, to ensure compliance with local law, and to make any modifications to the Policy that may be necessary

Personally-identifying information that users submit through our website is encrypted for secure transmission and stored in password-protected databases with restricted access. Only designated individuals at Project HOPE have access to personal information provided by website users and donors.

**Your Privacy Rights**

You have a right to access and control your personal data that we have collected and stored. Accordingly, you may ask for a copy of any personal information about you that we have collected and stored or processed. We will provide you with a copy with reasonable promptness and at no expense. You may also ask that we correct, update or delete any of your personal data. Project HOPE adheres to the following individual rights when collecting and processing personal data:

1. Right to be informed
2. Right of access
3. Right to rectification
4. Right to erase
5. Right to restrict processing
6. Right to data portability
7. Right to object (including direct marketing)
8. Right to no automated decision making or profiling

**Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information**

We also collect non-personal information – data in a form that does not provide direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

**Normal Web Browsing  
**The information we gather during normal browsing comes from two sources: standard server logs collect information such as the IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, browser type, operating system; and information such as the site that referred you to us, the files you downloaded, the pages you visited, and the dates/times of those visits. We may use this information to improve our outreach and communications about our work.

Additionally, if you have come into the site from one of our newsletters or from a site that has requested a link to us, we will ask your browser to accept a cookie that carries a general marketing source code with you as you browse through the site, in order to help us match referring site to donations made. This cookie does not capture or hold any personally identifying information about you, and is deleted when you end your session by leaving our site or closing your browser.

**Cookies and Other Technologies**

When you visit our website, we might store some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” (i.e. a small piece of text that stores information on your browser in your computer’s hard drive) or similar file. We use conversion tracking cookies as part of campaigns in order to analyze trends, gather broad demographic information, and monitor site traffic patterns that can help us further develop and improve the design and functionality of our site. Similarly, we also use cookies for ”retargeting” in our internet advertising campaigns so that third party vendors, including Google, can show you advertising about Project HOPE as you browse the internet. Retargeting is a marketing tool that identifies you as a previous visitor to the Project HOPE website and targets you for specific outreach messages, encouraging you to revisit our website or consider donating. The cookies will only be used to obtain non-personal information (you will be anonymous). If you prefer, you can usually set your browser to refuse cookies, or to notify you when you receive a new cookie. You can also opt out of receiving cookies on the Project HOPE website for Google advertising by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page (http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/#toc-edit).

Text messaging originator opt-in data and consent will not be shared with any third parties unless required by law.

By providing your phone number you consent to receive text messages and calls from Project HOPE. Msg. & data rates may apply. Text STOP to quit. Please read our [Privacy Policy](https://www.projecthope.org/privacy-policy/). Frequency may vary.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any other questions, requests, comments or concerns related to this Privacy Policy, please reach out to us at [hope@projecthope.org](mailto:hope@projecthope.org).

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. However, we will communicate any significant modifications of this Privacy Policy on our website

**Effective Date:** This Privacy Policy is Effective as of May 24, 2018

Sign up to receive the latest news and alerts from Project HOPE
---------------------------------------------------------------

Enter your email address(Required)

Submit        

Thank you for signing up for news and information alerts from Project HOPE!

1220 19th Street, NW, Suite 800  
Washington, DC 20036  
Telephone: 844-349-0188

Project HOPE is an international  
nonprofit 501(c)(3) organization.  
Tax ID #: 53-0242962

### Explore

### Follow us on social to join the community

Donate to Project HOPE and help save lives
------------------------------------------

Donation type One Time  Monthly 

Donation amount, one time $25  $50  $100 

Donation amount, monthly $10  $25  $50 

Donation amount, other Other donation amount 

Donate Now

Proud to be independently verified by:
--------------------------------------

© 2024 Project HOPE. All Rights Reserved.

Close Donation Form

Give with confidence.
---------------------

Please make a compassionate gift today to help save lives around the world. Your support means more children and families can get the vital medicines and care they need now — and that health workers will have the training and support they need to save lives for years to come.

Donation type One Time  Monthly 

Donation amount, one time $25  $50  $100 

Donation amount, monthly $10  $25  $50 

Donation amount, other Other donation amount 

Donate Now

We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. By clicking “Accept”, you consent to us using data collected from the cookies on our website. To learn more, check out our [privacy policy](https://www.projecthope.org/privacy-policy).

Accept
